jobbuddy.ie 2014-04-02

# Irish Jobs | Ireland Jobs - Irish Jobs Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy Statement

Jobbuddy   respect your right to privacy and comply with our obligations under the Data Protection. The purpose of this Website Privacy Policy is to outline how we deal with any personal data you provide to us while visiting this website. By visiting this website, you are accepting the terms of this Website Privacy Policy. Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such, and we are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these other websites.

1\. Types of Information Collected

We retain two types of information:

(a)   Personal Data

(b)    This is data that identifies you or can be used to identify, contact you or process applications on your behalf and may include your name, address, email address, detailed financial information, user IP addresses in circumstances where they have not been deleted, clipped or anonymised, telephone number, and billing and credit history information. Such information is only collected from you if you voluntarily submit it to us or have authorised us to obtain it.

(c)    Non-Personal Data

Like most web sites, we gather statistical and other analytical information collected on an aggregate basis of all visitors to our web site. This Non-Personal Data comprises information that cannot be used to identify or contact you, such as demographic information regarding, for example, user IP addresses where they have been clipped or anonymised, browser types and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of our web site.

2.Purposes for which we hold your Information

(a) Personal Data

We will process any Personal Data you provide to us for the following purposes:

(i) To provide you with the goods or services you have ordered;

(ii) To contact you if required in connection with your enquiry  or to respond to any communications you might send to us

(iii) To send various promotional material such as monthly newsletters.

(b) Non-Personal Data

 We use the Non-Personal Data gathered from visitors to our website in an aggregate form to get a better understanding of where our visitors come from and to help us better design and organise our website.

3\. Cookies

Jobbuddy website uses "cookie" technology. A cookie is a little piece of text stored by the browser on your computer, at the request of our server. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your personal preferences so you do not have to re-enter them each time you connect to our website - our cookies are not available to other websites. You are always free to decline our cookies, if your browser permits, or to ask your browser to indicate when a cookie is being sent. You can also delete cookie files from your computer at your discretion. Note that if you decline our cookies or ask for notification each time a cookie is being sent, this may affect your ease of use of this website.

4\. Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

We may provide Non-Personal Data to third parties, where such information is combined with similar information of other users of our web site. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit our web site, the demographic breakdown of our community users of our web site, or the activities that visitors to our web site engage in while on our web site. The third parties to whom we may provide this information may include potential or actual advertisers, providers of advertising services (including web site tracking services), commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties. We will not disclose your Personal Data to third parties unless you have consented to this disclosure or unless the third party is required to fulfil your service order (in such circumstances, the third party is bound by similar data protection requirements. We will disclose your Personal Data if we believe in good faith that we are required to disclose it in order to comply with any applicable law, a summons, a search warrant, a court or regulatory order, or other statutory requirement.

5.Sale of Business

We reserve the right to transfer information (including your Personal Data) to a third party in the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, receivership or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of our company provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of the Web Site Privacy Policy and provided that the third party only uses your Personal Data for the purposes that you provided it to us. You will be notified in the event of any such transfer and you will be afforded an opportunity to opt-out.

6.Security

Your Personal Data is encrypted and  held on secured servers with our hosting providers. The nature of the Internet is such that we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us via the Internet. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. However, we will take all reasonable steps (including appropriate technical and organisational measures) to protect your Personal Data.

7.Updating, Verifying and Deleting Personal Data

You may inform us of any changes in your Personal Data, and in accordance with our obligations under the Data Protection Acts  on the Protection of Individuals with regard to the Processing of Personal Data and on the Free Movement of Such Data, and any implementing and/or amending legislation as may be adopted in Ireland  from time to time, we will update or delete your Personal Data accordingly. To find out what Personal Data we hold on you or to have your Personal Data updated, amended or removed from our database, please contact Jobbuddy. Any such data subject requests may be subject to the prescribed fee.

8\. Jobbuddy Profile

Jobbuddy provides registered members with the option of creating a personal profile. A profile includes your CV, employment and educational history, contact details, minimum salary expectation and the classifications and locations ('Profile') registered members would like to work in. Registered members' profiles can be seen by Jobbuddy clients who place job ads in matching classifications and locations. Members can of course choose to hide their profile at any time. Registered members' Profiles will remain  anonymous until the Jobbuddy client purchases access to a registered members CV and contact details. Jobbuddy provides registered members with the following privacy options in relation to the access allowed to their Profile:

Provide resume and contact details immediately

When a Jobbuddy client purchases a registered member’s Profile that resume and the contact details in that resume will be emailed immediately to the relevant JOBBUDDY client.

Hide or delete Profile

Registered members can elect to hide their Profile, so JOBBUDDY clients cannot see Private Profile at all, whilst allowing the Profile to be stored in the My Account area of the site. Alternatively Registered Members can elect to delete their Profile. Deleting a Profile from the My Account area of the site will mean it is no longer accessible to the registered member. Please note that deleted Profiles may still be stored by JOBBUDDY in testing or backup systems for a period of time.

All information provided when creating a Profile including name, resume, email address, telephone numbers, employment and educational history are used for the purposes of facilitating registered members job seeking efforts.

Registered Members can modify, hide or delete their resume at any time.

JOBBUDDY reserves the right to disable or delete a Profile at their sole discretion.

9\. Online Applications

Making an online application to a job advertisement on JOBBUDDY is a free and optional service that does not require registration. Job applications require you to complete mandatory fields (first name, last name, phone and email) so that the advertiser can identify and contact you. Your application, including attachments and cover letters, are forwarded directly on to the third party advertiser and Registered users have the option of saving their resumes and cover letters. This information may also be disclosed to JOBBUDDY's service providers and contractors from time to time who assist us to deliver our products and services.

By applying to a position advertised on JOBBUDDY you are requesting that JOBBUDDY pass the information to the Advertiser as a part of your application.

Additionally, you have the right to request your personal information direct from Advertisers on JOBBUDDY.

10\. Email communications from JOBBUDDY

JOBBUDDY also provides you with selected information about job seeking and career-related topics in our email newsletter JOBBUDDY News Update. This free service is sent to registered users and provides the option of opting out of receiving these. JOBBUDDY may also make you aware of additional products and services which form part of your relationship with JOBBUDDY.

11\. Storage & Security of Personal Information

JOBBUDDY takes all reasonable steps to ensure the security of our system. JOBBUDDY allows you to access your information at any time to keep it accurate and up to date. Any information which we hold for you is stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities.

In addition, our employees and the contractors who provide services related to our information systems are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by JOBBUDDY. However, JOBBUDDY will not be held responsible for events arising from unauthorised access of your personal information.

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure, by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the JOBBUDDY site. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorised use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security.

12\. JOBBUDDY Partners & Advertisers

JOBBUDDY provides links and passes online application to third party sites. The use of your information by these third party sites is not within the control of JOBBUDDY and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of these companies.

With the consent of JOBBUDDY's registered members, JOBBUDDY may provide that member's personal profile to JOBBUDDY clients who have placed job ads with matching classifications and locations to the registered member's profile and who have purchased access to the member's profile.. The use of that information by these JOBBUDDY clients is not within the control of JOBBUDDY and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of these clients.

JOBBUDDY clients who place job ads on JOBBUDDY, and who purchase JOBBUDDY registered members' profiles are asked to comply with Irish privacy policy with regard to their own information handling practices.

You may also directly contact advertisers to request access to any personal information that you have sent as part of an application or as part of a profile.

13\. Feedback

JOBBUDDY welcomes ideas and feedback about all aspects of the site. JOBBUDDY stores feedback that users send to us. This feedback will be used to administer and refine the service and may be shared with JOBBUDDY partners either in aggregate form or with specific identifying characteristics removed.

14.Changes to the Website Privacy Policy

Any changes to this Web Site Privacy Policy will be posted on this web site so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any time we decide to use Personal Data in a manner significantly different from that stated in this Web Site Privacy Policy, or otherwise disclosed to you at the time it was collected, we will notify you by email, and you will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in the new manner.

 15\. Cookie Policy

To give you the best possible job search experience, this site uses cookies. Continuing to use Jobuddy.ie means you agree to our use of cookies. This document (anchorlink to cookie policy )   explains “what cookies are” and the types of cookies Jobbuddy  uses on our  websites.

What are cookies?

A "cookie" is a text file that websites send to a visitor's computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor's browser or to store information or settings in the browser

Does Jobbuddy.ie use cookies on its websites?

Yes. Jobbuddy  uses cookies on its websites to enhance the website and provide services and functionality to its  users. You may restrict or disable the use of cookies through your web browser; however, without cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features of the websites.

What types of cookies are used on our website?

Strictly Necessary Cookies

These cookies are essential in order to carry out a transaction or request initiated by you. Strictly necessary cookies are essential for the use of the features on Jobbuddy.ie. Examples include, remembering information provided by you as you move through the site to apply for jobs, purchase job credits, track your application, using our Applicant Tracking System and Interview Scheduler and managing your logged-in status during the session.

Functional Cookies

These cookies allow the website to remember choices you have made in order to provide functionality for your benefit. For example, functional cookies allow the website to remember settings specific to you, such as your country selection and persistent logged-in state if selected by you, and display application status, jobs applied, reviewed and other customized features.

Analytic Cookies

These cookies allow us to collect data relating to your use of the website, including the content on which you click while browsing the website, in order to improve the performance and design of the website.

These cookies may be provided our third party analytic tool provider but are only used for purposes related to our websites. We use  Google Analytics to analyse how jobbuddy.ie is used

Targeting Cookies

These cookies remember information regarding your use of the website so that we can serve promotional and other targeted information to you on our website.

How do I disable or remove cookies?

Each type of web browser offers ways to restrict and delete cookies.  For more information on how to manage cookies visit the appropriate link below.
